# 我跟你说这个菜 我告诉你
You know what,
# 都能火遍整个中国 太健康了
it’s going to be popular all over China by it’s healthiness.
# 下一个节目 汆水蛋
up coming show: Cuan Shui dan(boiled egg with Chinese chives).
# 据说这水蛋是奶奶传承的
I heard that this dish is heritaged from your grandma?
# 对我奶奶传承给我
Yeah, My grandma past it to me.
# 我再教给我徒弟
And I taught it to my disciples.
# 徒弟的味道做的还真不对
However, my disciples couldn’t get the flavor right.
# 就简单东西
for such a simple recipe,
# 后来我告诉他细节在哪
until I told him where the tricky part is.
# 你看见没有大爷 火咱先点上
Look,Da Ye. Frist we turn on the stove.
# 把韭菜切的跟馅儿似的
Chop the chives like making stuffing.
# 就是切馅儿一样
it’s just like how you make stuffing.
# 你看 在家里这道菜
Look, cooking this dish back at home,
# 既好吃又营养 还谁都能做
it's both delicious and healthy.; and everyone can make it.
# 但是就有一个窍门
but there’s just one trick.
# 一会儿我在制作当中
I will talk about it later during the process.
# 我给你们讲了
You know what,
# 要不讲永远也不知道
If I don’t point it out, people will never know.
# 还真不好吃
and it won’t taste good.
# 半斤韭菜 六个鸡蛋
250 grams of chives with six eggs.
# 其实现在鸡蛋没有
the egg nowadays does not
# 过去奶奶那时候做的好吃
taest as good as eggs from grandma’s age.
# 没有那鸡蛋好
not tasty as their eggs.
# 水量一定要充足
water has to be sufficient
# 为什么说健康
Why do I say it’s healthy,
# 你看不加淀粉 就是韭菜鸡蛋
you see I don’ t put starch,just chives and eggs.
# 不加淀粉不加盐
No starch, no salt.
# 你看这就行了 直接下锅
Look, that’s it. Directly into the pot.
# 这个火要大了 你看可以小一点
if there’s too much heat, you can turn it down a bit
# 微微的小一点 别太小了
just turn down a little bit, not too much.
# 燉熟 这就叫燉
simmer it done. This is called simmer.
# 燉熟
simmer it done.
# 这也是一种很奇妙的技巧
this is also an interesting technique.
# 慢推慢燉
slowly push, slowly simmer.
# 你看说这菜简单
The dish looks easy,
# 但是它确实需要一定的技法
but needs quite a bit of technique
# 你看二位大师帮着我忙活这点事
You two masters are helping me for this simple task.
# 我主要是掌握一个火力
I’m just controling the heat.
# 这菜简单吗 它不简单
Is the dish easy? No it’s not.
# 往往有些菜
There is always dishes
# 越简单的方法是越不简单
looks simple but acctully not.
# 平凡当中没有平凡 对不平凡
what's common is not common
# 简单当中又不简单
it’s simple but not easy.
# 你看 还是不行
still not yet.
# 开锅了你看
see, it’s boiling now
# 是开锅 是不开锅呢
You want it boil or not?
# 得开一点
just boil a little bit.
# 但是也别完全开大了
but not over boiled.
# 把鸡蛋得给它煮熟了
just get the egg cooked.
# 水汆
boiling a little bit.
# 似开非开
semes boil but not fully boil.
# 大家已经是静下来了
it’s getting quiet.
# 这是沁熟的
this is cooked through soaking
# 有点像鸡豆花啊 对啊
like how we cook Ji Dou Hua. Right?
# 这马上该熟了
almost cooked now.
# 这沫子可以要可以不要
it’s opptional to leave the foam here or not.
# 基本就快熟了
it’s basically done.
# 马上该熟了
it should be cooked.
# 鲜嫩 这韭菜本身也提鲜
tender and flavorful, and the chives also make it flavorful.
# 关火了
turning off the stove
# 你看这水太多了
You see, it’s too much of water.
# 豆花似的
just like dou hua.
# 关键的来了
now here is the point.
# 酱油 您觉得咸味够不够
soy sauce, do you think it’s salty enough?
# 什么酱油都行 够了
any kind of soy sauce. that’s enough.
# 这咸味够不够 够了
it it enough salt? that’s enough.
# 你看这个温度多少度啊
What do you think is the temperature?
# 到不了八十度吧 到不了
less than 80C? probeblly not there.
# 就是说这种情况下
in this case,
# 为什么是健康菜
why is it a healthy dish?
# 这味精一点毒素没有
MSG does not have negative effects.
# 就把这点味精就加进去就行了
just put this bit of MSG in it.
# 香油
sesame oil
# 这个菜我是今天头一次
it’s my first time see the process
# 亲自在现场看见的
live in person.
# 过去是在电视上孙大师做过
I used to see Master Sun making it on TV.
# 做过之后再也没做过
afterwards,it’s never been cooked again.
# 你再不做也失传了
the process is lost if you don't make it.
# 这个菜极嫩
this dish is extremely tender.
# 大哥你看这就完了
it’s done by now.
# 您看 一会您尝尝
look, try it later.
# 我跟你说这个菜
You know what about this dish,
# 我告诉你都能火遍整个中国
I tell you it’s going to be popular all over China.
# 太健康了
It’s too healthy.
# 大爷迫切的吃上了
Da Ye can't wait to try it.
# 急的吃上了
He can’t wait
# 嫩 真鲜
it’s tender, and so flavourful.
# 千万别加酱油了 正好 够咸
No more soy sauce, it’s good, salty enough.
# 最关键的东西你知道在哪儿么
you know what’s the tricky part is?
# 我是说还是不说跟网友们
Should I tell all our audiance?
# 那肯定得说
You have to say it.
# 您发现没有 这韭菜都是脆的
You see, the chive is crispy.
# 我跟你说 我说是不说
Should I keep it a secret?
# 必须说
You must say.
# 要说了就没有秘密了谁都能做
If I give it out, everyone is able to make it.
# 要什么秘密
no more mystery
# 现在你孙大师胸怀这么大
Master Sun you are broadminded,
# 孙大师你就叫网友们学会了
just let our audiance learn.
# 人也知道你奶奶啊
so that we also know your grandma’s recipy
# 其实我一揭秘您就知道了
it’s quite obvious
# 我关火调味
I turned off the stove to season it.
# 如果说你要开着火 有一点火调味
If you season it with the stove on,
# 这菜马上这味道就变了
the flavor would change immediately.
# 它必须香油 味精 酱油不能着热
sesame oil, MSG, soy sauce are sensitive to heat
“我是大爷”00:05:02,
I am Da Ye.